(This drama is related to specific characters, institutions, and groups It has nothing to do with the case and is purely fictitious (I hereby inform you)
(本剧与特定人物 机构 团体 案件无关 纯属虚构 特此告知)
(development of the modern world)
(现代世界的发展)
(We buy and sell books)
(我们收购与贩卖书籍)
Brother, come out
哥 你出来
Come out for a moment
出来一下
What's wrong
怎么了
(Flowers blooming in Buzhuang)
(花开布庄)
(Yuanzu Dumplings and Steamed Buns)
(元祖饺子馒头)
Hello
喂
Brother, that girl is very beautiful, right?
哥 那个丫头很漂亮吧
Let's go over there and have a look
我们过去那边看看
Li Douxue
李斗学
Come out quickly
快点出来
(Gwangju Prison in the early 1980s)
(1980年代初期 光州监狱)
Really, what are you doing?
真是的 你们在搞什么
You'll be dead when I get out
等我出去你们就死定了
Li Douxue, someone came to visit the prisoner
李斗学 有人来探监
Tonight at eight o'clock That brat...
今天晚间八点 那个臭小子…
Room 8 2-5 Really annoying
8号房2-5 真让人不爽
Perform pest control and disinfection
进行害虫防治消毒
(Lishui, late 1970s)
(1970年代末期 丽水)
What are you doing? Eat quickly and then go out.
你在干嘛 快点吃一吃就出去吧
Don't keep Tetsuo waiting too long
别让哲雄等太久
Really, he's going to have indigestion
真是的 他要消化不良了
Soak it in water and eat it
泡水吃一吃啦
ok dad
好的 爸
I want it too
我也要
You little girl
你这小丫头
Your school is very close. Just eat slowly.
你的学校很近 慢慢吃就好
You should eat more
你再多吃点啦
My son is so handsome
我儿子长得真帅
(National meritorious person’s name: Cui Bingzhe) Study hard
(国家有功者 姓名:崔炳喆) 好好念书
If you fight with your brothers, you will never lose.
要是跟哥哥们打架 绝对不能输
Whatever happens, mom will help you solve it
出什么事妈妈都会帮你解决
Your son is not inferior to others in studying You won't lose in a fight
你儿子念书不输人 打架也不会输人的
As expected of my good son
不愧是我的乖儿子
Drink it in one gulp
一口气喝掉
Tetsuo, why don't you come out quickly?
哲雄 你还不赶快出来吗
Douxue is waiting for you
斗学在等你
Come on, your dad is going to be angry.
快走吧 你爸要生气了
I have a date with someone tonight. I'll be back later.
我晚上跟人有约 会晚点回来
Okay, don't drink too much
好 你别喝太多酒
Please walk slowly
请慢走
Be careful on the road Be careful on the road
路上小心    路上小心
Goodbye…
再见…
we went to school
我们去上学了
go ahead
去吧
You two are always inseparable It's very reassuring
你们两个总是形影不离 让人很放心呢
Like brothers. Looks great.
就像亲兄弟一样 看起来真不错
What's wrong?
怎么了吗
Nothing
没什么啦
My brother and I were like brothers
我跟哥本来就像亲兄弟一样
We're going to be late. Let's go.
要迟到了 我们快走吧
Let's go
快走吧
Be careful on the road
路上小心
Why did you specially send your son out?
你怎么还特别送你儿子出来
I didn't come out to see him off.
我不是要送他才出来的
I want to help Qingzi do it together Just a side dish for the kids.
我是要帮庆子一起做 孩子们的小菜才来的
I'm going to make fried anchovies and a few side dishes...
我打算做炒鳀鱼和几样小菜…
Yes, after all, my mother is a scholar The craftsmanship is very good
对啊 毕竟斗学的妈妈 手艺很好嘛
Why are you still so ignorant?
你怎么还是那么不懂事
The fields have been very busy recently
最近田里忙得很
Why do you call people here for such a trivial matter?
怎么为这点小事就把人家叫来
Oh, don't say that. I'm not busy at all.
唉唷 你别这么说 我一点都不忙
My mother-in-law just happened to send it Good quality anchovies...
刚好我娘家寄了 品质不错的鳀鱼来…
No need I just...
不用了 我就…
Thank you very much for your consideration
虽然很感谢您的心意
But this is related to the education of children
但这关乎到孩子的教育问题
Please come back
您请回吧
Come in quickly
快进来
(city bus)
(市内公车)
The train is about to leave
要发车了
We are going to school... Go quickly...
我们要去上学… 快走…
"The years are gone forever"
"岁月一去不复返"
(The heyday of Yingzi) "I heard this sentence once when I was young and frivolous"
(英子的全盛时代) "年少轻狂时我曾听过这句话"
From today on, we will only have half-day classes on Saturdays
从今天起星期六就只上半天课
The movie will be shown in urban areas
这部电影会在市区上映
I heard it's very pretty. How about it?
听说超好看耶 怎么样
You are looking for death
你找死喔
Besides, we look like students at first sight. How can I get in?
何况我们一看就是学生 怎么进得去
Why are you so timid?
你怎么这么胆小
Sit down
坐一下吧
Get up
起来
I'm gonna wake you up, brat
我叫你起来 臭小子
You guys in the second grade are not big or small.
你这二年级的家伙没大没小的
He even asked the senior to stand Sit on your own
竟然让学长站着 自己坐在位子上
But neither are you It’s time for me to respect the elderly and give way to the virtuous.
但你们也不是 需要我敬老尊贤让位的年纪吧
Brat, what did you say?
臭小子 你说什么
What do you want to do, brat?
你想干嘛 臭小子
Are you really studying a year late?
你是真的晚读一年吗
If you don't believe it
不信的话
Just go to our school by yourself Look at Li Douxue's student record book.
就自己去我们学校 找李斗学的学生纪录簿来看
Let’s talk about that later, bastard
那个之后再说 混帐东西
Brat
臭小子
well played
打得好
Come on
来啊
Brat One more punch
臭小子 再来一拳
Damn it, you took advantage of people's unpreparedness
可恶 竟然趁人不备
Come here quickly
快点放马过来
Brother, we are going to be late for school
哥 我们上学要迟到了
Let's go
快走吧
good
好
That's ok
可以了吧
Let's go
走吧
Brother, we are really going to be late
哥 我们真的要迟到了
Hello…
喂…
(Practice that focuses on security and education)
(全力进行安保和教育的实践)
Close the door
关门
Hello…
喂…
Put it on quickly
快点换上
You shouldn't be able to tell, right?
应该看不出来吧
It's really getting thicker and thicker.
真是越垫越厚了
These brats
这群臭小子
Your butts are really unlucky
你们的屁股还真够倒楣
Follow the wrong master and get beaten every morning
跟错主人只好每天早上挨揍
Look at these two guys
看看这两个家伙
Can read a little bit
稍微会读点书
The principal said it doesn't matter if you are late.
校长就说你们迟到也没关系
Guys like you are the worst. You are bad enough.
你们这种家伙最恶劣 有够恶劣
Don't let me get up
不准给我起来
Lie down for me
给我趴好
No movement allowed
不准乱动
The midterm exam results are out
期中考结果出来了
Hey, congratulations to you bunch of pig heads.
喂 恭喜你们这群猪脑袋
Our class this time Also the last one in the second grade
我们班这次 也是二年级的最后一名
Although Cui Zhexiong maintained the number one ranking in the school,
虽然崔哲雄守住了全校排名第一
Li Douxue ranked second in the school
李斗学则是全校排名第二
Still can't clean up our class The stigma of being at the bottom of the grade
还是洗刷不了我们班 在全年级垫底的污名
What is a class?
何谓的班级是什么
life community
生命共同体
What will happen to everyone
所有人都要怎样
take responsibility
负起责任
The whole class went to the playground and ran five laps
全班去操场跑五圈
You bunch of brats Still unclear about the situation?
你们这群臭小子 还搞不清楚状况吗
Move quickly
快点动起来
Why don't you go out quickly?
还不赶快出去
Really, if you hate me, just say so.
真是的 讨厌我就直说
Why bother talking about education?
何必扯什么教育问题
How amazing she is
她是有多了不起
So, didn’t I tell you not to go?
所以说啊 我不是叫你别去了吗
Why did you go there and ask for trouble?
干嘛过去自讨苦吃
And to be honest
而且说句实在话
He graduated from a university in Seoul
人家可是从首尔的大学毕业的
There's no woman around here who's more knowledgeable than her.
这附近哪有比她更有学识的女人
what did you say
你说什么
This big brother Who were you talking to just now?
这位大哥 你刚刚是在帮谁说话啊
I'm talking about doing housework
我说的是做家事
What’s the use of graduating from college?
大学毕业有什么用
Are you good at cooking after graduating from college?
大学毕业就很会做菜吗
Still good at washing clothes
还是很会洗衣服了
Compared with housework skills
要比家事技能的话
I'm a university professor
我可是大学教授的等级呢
Okay, you go and be your professor
好 你就去当你的教授
But I've said it thousands of times
但我说过几千遍了
Keep some distance from that house.
和那户人家保持点距离吧
Abominable
可恶
(The heyday of Yingzi)
(英子的全盛时代)
Hey, look over there...
喂 你看那边…
In front of the proud Taegeukgi flag
在让人自豪的太极旗面前
For the endless glory of the motherland and nation
为了祖国和民族的无尽荣耀
Uncle… Give us all
大叔… 献上我们的全部
Can he hear you like this?
你这样他听得到吗
Uncle… Determined to serve the country with loyalty
大叔… 决心精忠报国
What time is it?
几点了
The movie is about to start
电影马上要开演了
(Kowloon Sports Center) He should come out
(九龙体育馆) 他应该会出来吧
Won't we get caught doing this?
我们这样不会被抓到吗
what are you doing here
你们在这里做什么
us?
我们吗
That's right. Otherwise, who else is here?
对啊 不然这里还有谁
What about you?
那你呢
I know without looking
我不用看也知道
You two bad boys Want to sneak into the theater through the back door?
你们这两个不良少年 想从后门溜进戏院里吧
What are you talking about? This little thing is real.
你说什么 这小不点真是的
Then what are you doing here?
那你在这里干嘛
This is my home. What's wrong?
这是我家 怎么了
Really, is this girl’s head shell broken?
真是的 这丫头是头壳坏掉吗
How could he tell such an outrageous lie?
竟然会说出这么离谱的谎话
You guys get out of here, or I'm going to call someone here.
你们滚蛋 不然我要叫人来了
You are so funny
你还真搞笑
We were legitimately invited
我们是正正当当被邀请来的
Don't mess with big brother
你不要招惹大哥哥
Let's go play while I'm in a good mood.
在我好声好气时去一边玩吧
Dingchen, you are here
定辰 你来啦
Are you from a lumber factory?
你们是木材工厂的人吗
Yes
对
Uncle, did you ask them to come?
大叔 是你叫他们来的吗
This is a long story
这个说来话长
In short, because My friend works in a lumber factory
简言之是因为 我的朋友在木材工厂工作
That friend asked me to let them watch the movie...
那个朋友拜托我让他们看电影…
Kick them out immediately
马上把他们赶出去
Otherwise I will file a complaint with my father.
不然我就要跟我爸告状了
You girl are so unreasonable and unforgiving
你这丫头真是得理不饶人
Then let me ask you
那我问你
What about you sneaking in through the back door to watch a movie?
你从后门溜进来看电影的事
Does your dad know
你爸知道吗
Does he know
他知不知道
Don't go further and further
你不要越来越过分喔
What does this have to do with you...
这关你什么事…
Who are you?
你算老几啊
Don't be like this
你们不要这样嘛
I might not be able to come back in a short time.
我说不定短时间内无法再来了
why
为什么呢
It seems like something good is going to happen
似乎有好事要发生了
what's going on
是什么事
Thank you for inviting us to watch the movie
感谢你请我们看电影
What nonsense are you talking about? How could she invite us to watch a movie?
你胡说什么 她哪有请我们看电影
Watch free movies at our theater What's the difference between giving me a treat?
到我们家戏院看免费电影 跟我请客有什么两样
You are not allowed to appear around here again.
你们以后不准再出现在这附近了
Do you know?
知道了没
I'll give you this sentence
这句话还给你
That's your dad's theater, not yours
那是你爸的戏院 又不是你的
Could it be yours?
难不成是你的吗
what did you say
你说什么
You two guys who look like potatoes
你们这两个长得像马铃薯的家伙
We are not like potatoes Have you ever seen a potato that looks so handsome?
我们才不像马铃薯呢 你看过长那么帅的马铃薯吗
No
没有吧
Want to explode
要爆罗
Really Really loud
真是的 还真大声
Oh, you two
唉唷 你们两个
Brother, they are those brats
哥 就是那群臭小子
What a brat, big or small
真是没大没小的臭小子
How dare you seduce a little girl when you are still young? what to do
乳臭未干还敢勾引小丫头 怎么办
Hanging around the theater Did you see what he had in his hand?
在戏院附近晃来晃去 看到他手上的东西了吧
Brother, run quickly
哥 快跑
Run quickly...
快点跑啊…
where to run
要往哪里跑
Brother, are you okay?
哥 你没事吧
Catch the two brats
抓住两个臭小子
"The years are gone forever"
"岁月一去不复返"
"I heard this sentence once when I was young and frivolous"
"年少轻狂时我曾听过这句话"
are you okay
你没事吧
"My lover who left Wanshou Mountain"
"我那离开万寿山的爱人"
catch them quickly
快抓住他们
Catching up
追上来了
Run quickly
快跑
"Hope to see her again today"
"希望今天能再见到她一面"
"With my lips full of sorrow and joy"
"用我充满悲喜的双唇"
"Although I can speak freely, I just want to say"
"虽能够畅所欲言 但我只想说"
"I live so ignorantly" (Wutong Wood Factory)
"我活得是如此不懂事" (梧桐木材工厂)
Where did they go?
他们跑去哪里了
What are you still doing here?
你们还愣在这里干嘛
OK
好的
Oh my God, there are rats... Oh my god
天啊 有老鼠… 妈呀
lied to you
骗你的
Why are you like that?
你干嘛那样啦
Just kidding
开个玩笑嘛
Come over here...
过来这边…
Abominable
可恶
This is my dad's lumber factory.
这边都是我爸的木材工厂
I should go to the pharmacy first.
应该要先去一下药局吧
Her legs are hurt
她的腿都受伤了
If you show up in front of me again
你们要是再出现在我面前
He will die in my hands then
到时就会死在我手里
Accomplish complete
Accomplish 完成
Adventure event adventure
Adventure 事件 冒险
Adventure…
Adventure…
what are you doing
你在做什么
scared me
吓我一跳
when did you come
你什么时候来的
Just now, why are you so scared?
刚刚 不过你怎么吓成这样
It's okay. I was just memorizing English vocabulary words.
没事 我刚刚在背英文单字
Hey what are you doing
喂 你干嘛
I said I was memorizing English words just now
我说了我刚刚在背英文单字
To the girl whose name I don’t know
致不知道名字的少女
Is this memorizing English words?
这是在背英文单字吗
My name is Li Douxue
我的名字叫做李斗学
I'm really sorry about what happened at the theater last time
上次在戏院的事真的很抱歉
It makes me worried and troubled all the time...
让我耿耿于怀 一直很烦恼…
Is this a love letter to that girl?
这是要写给那个丫头的情书吗
That's not a love letter
那才不是情书
I saw that her knees were all skinned that day.
我看她那天膝盖都破皮了
I wrote this because I felt so sorry.
心里过意不去才写的
I didn't mean to give this letter to her
我没有要把这封信给她
Then why did your face become so red?
那你的脸怎么变得那么红
That...because the sun is very big
那个…因为太阳很大
Really, will I still not understand you?
真是的 我还会不了解你吗
Let's be honest with each other
我们就对彼此坦诚点吧
Are you like me?
你跟我一样吧
I think that girl’s face Just lingering in front of my eyes
觉得那丫头的面容 就在眼前挥之不去
The heart beats like a drum Make a buzzing noise in your ears
心跳声仿佛鼓声般 在耳边咚咚作响吧
Brother, have you ever won me?
哥 你赢得过我吗
Who said I would fight with you?
谁说要跟你争了
I'm really not interested in her It's up to you to decide
我真的对她没兴趣 你自己看着办吧
Brother, don’t think of me as a despicable person.
哥 你不要把我当成卑鄙小人喔
If you also have a crush on her We have to compete openly and honestly.
要是你也对她有好感 我们就要堂堂正正来竞争才行
And compared to the two of us,
而且比起我们两个的心意
That girl's thoughts are the most important, right?
那丫头的想法最重要吧
She is not a girl whose name is unknown
她不是不知道名字的少女
Her name is Wu Dingchen
她叫吴定辰
Studying in the second grade of Lishui Girls' High School
就读丽水女高二年级
She just transferred here at the beginning of this year
她是今年初才转来的
I heard that her father originally opened a theater in Seoul
听说她爸原本在首尔开戏院
I came to the south to recuperate because of health reasons.
因为健康因素才来到南部休养
She followed
她就跟着来了
But do you know what’s most amazing?
不过 你知道最神奇的是什么吗
This isn't the first time we've seen her
我们并不是第一次见到她
what
什么
Don't you remember?
你不记得了吗
It was at the Zhennan Festival before The captain of the honor team I saw
就是之前在镇南祭上 看到的仪队队长
Do you remember
你记得吧
The girl twirling the baton
转着指挥棒的那个丫头
it's her
就是她
Really?
真的吗
If you want to chase someone
想要追人家的话
At least you need to know this information, right?
至少要知道这些情报 不是吗
We are Korean athletes
我们是大韩健儿
Majestic, brave and good at fighting
威风凛凛 骁勇善战
Excellent physical strength and strong skills...
体力过人 身手矫健…
Eat it...
吃吧…
Thank you. You're welcome. I will enjoy it
谢谢 我们就不客气了 我会好好享用的
Alas, everyone is here
唉唷 大家都来啦
They're all gathered together
全都齐聚一堂了呢
No need to get up. Please sit down...
不用起来 请坐…
Alas, you are here
唉唷 您来啦
You are here
您来啦
Everyone, let’s have fun today OK
各位今天就尽情地玩吧 好的
OMG…
天啊…
Alas... Dad, you are back
唉唷… 爸 您回来啦
The young master seems a little drunk
少爷好像有点醉了
Tetsuo
哲雄
yes dad
是的 爸
You want to live like your grandpa, you know?
你要活得像你爷爷那样 知道吗
Got it
知道了
no matter what others say
无论别人怎么说
Black is black, white is white
黑就是黑 白就是白
Why are you telling your child this? Come on in
你干嘛对孩子说这些 快进去吧
Got it…
知道了…
Alas, brother
唉唷 大哥
Sorry to cause you trouble
不好意思给你添麻烦
Please walk slowly
请慢走
Really, Master, don’t say that.
真是的 少爷你别这么说
You go in and have a rest.
你快进去休息吧
You go back, I'll go in first
你回去吧 我先进去了
please have a good rest
请好好休息
Uncle, thank you for your hard work
叔叔 辛苦您了
Your dad has a lot of worries
你爸有很多烦心的事
Just be considerate of him
你就体谅他吧
OK
好的
Tetsuo Every time I see you
哲雄 我每次看到你
I think you look a lot like your grandfather
都觉得你跟你爷爷长得很像
You will definitely be like your grandpa
你一定会跟你爷爷一样
become an excellent person
成为一个优秀的人
I wish I were a quarter of his size
我有像到他的四分之一就好了
Oh my god, even the modesty is like your grandpa.
天啊 连谦虚这点也像你爷爷呢
You are such a mature adult.
你真是个成熟的大人
I'm leaving I'm leaving
我要走了 我要离开了
Holding young son's hand
握着年幼儿子的手
Planting potatoes…
种马铃薯…
Douxue, dad is in a good mood today
斗学 爸今天心情很好
Dad, is that right?
爸 是吗
When I was staying with the young master in town
我在镇上跟少爷待在一起时
meet your teacher
遇到你的老师
He said when you were in high school Enrolled with first place score
他说你上高中时 是以第一名的成绩入学的
He said you came on stage to give a speech on behalf of all the freshmen.
他说你上台代表全体新生致词
Why didn't you tell me?
你怎么都没跟我说呢
I'm afraid if you go to school I have to treat everyone to dinner again
我怕你去学校的话 又得请大家吃饭
No matter how poor I am Just tell me
就算我再怎么穷 只要跟我说一声
Even if there is no way to kill a cow It's more than enough to slaughter a pig.
就算没办法宰头牛 宰头猪也是绰绰有余
Anyway, you know how to read and are polite
总之 你又会念书 又有礼貌
The teacher keeps praising you Say I taught you well
老师不断称赞你 说我把你教得很好
So I will ask your teacher Let’s have a cup of millet wine
所以我就请你们老师 喝杯小米酒了
But... don't do that again.
不过…你以后别再那样了
what
什么
How can you beat Tetsuo?
你怎么可以赢过哲雄呢
I heard that Tetsuo didn't get first place because He cried a lot about it
我听说哲雄因为没拿到第一名 他为此大哭了一场呢
The young master was just joking today Mention this to me
少爷今天才开玩笑似地 跟我提到这件事
Douxue, I've said it many times, right?
斗学 我说过很多次了吧
We must understand how to be a human being
我们要懂得做人的道理
No matter how smart you are, no matter how good you are at studying
无论再怎么聪明 再怎么会念书
If you don’t know how to be a human being
如果不懂得做人的道理
Then they are no different from pigs and cows
那么就跟猪牛没有两样
Whose fields are these?
这些是谁的田地
Who do I owe that I can barely read?
我是托谁的福 才能勉强识字
And let you live a life of adequate food and clothing
还让你们过上吃饱穿暖的日子呢
It's all thanks to Zhexiong and his grandfather.
都是托哲雄他爷爷的福啊
If you understand this
要是明白这点
You even stepped on the shadow of their family members You should also feel guilty
你连踩到他们家人的影子 也该觉得歉疚
So…
所以…
Don't take first place again
你别再拿第一名了
Don't beat others
不要赢过人家
Never beat Tetsuo in any aspect
在任何方面 都不要赢过哲雄
I said this, do you understand what I mean?
我这样说 你明白我的意思吗
I understand what you mean
我明白您的意思
But how long will I be like this?
但是 我要这样到什么时候
a lifetime
一辈子
Can you promise me
你能答应我吧
yes dad
是的 爸
I saw your toes this morning They all came out to say hello.
我今天早上看到你的脚趾头 都出来打招呼了
Your mother picked up a pair of worn-out shoes from somewhere
你妈不知道从哪里捡来一双破鞋
Did you see it?
看到了吗
Not yet
还没
Abominable
可恶
Do they really have to practice today?
她们今天真的有要练习吗
I heard with my own ears that there is an alumni sports meeting They will practice today
我亲耳听到因为要办校友运动会 她们今天会练习
It'll be out soon
待会就会出来了
You come down first
你先下来
Came out...
出来了…
Have you found her?
找到她了吗
Not yet. I haven't seen her yet.
还没 我还没看到她
Is she out?
她出来了吗
Has it come out?
到底出来了没
Really
真是的
Hi
嗨
how are you
你好吗
Really funny
还真搞笑
I said if you Appear in front of me again...
我说过你们要是 再出现在我面前…
will die in your hands
就会死在你手里
Right
对啊
Is it Bruce Lee?
是李小龙吗
You know so much
你知道得还真多
"Tangshan Big Brother" "Jingwu Sect" "The Dragon Crossing the River" and "Enter the Dragon"
"唐山大兄""精武门" "猛龙过江""龙争虎斗"
I've watched it dozens of times So I order nunchucks
我可是看了超过数十遍 所以会点双节棍
Come on, which one of you will die first?
来吧 你们谁要先受死
We have a wish before we die
我们在死前有个愿望
How about you die before you make a wish?
在许愿之前先受死吧 怎么样
what
什么
You two are not afraid of death Is there something wrong with your brain?
你们两个不怕死的 脑袋有问题吗
He tried his best to bully me before
之前拚命欺负我
What are you saying now? Do you want to date me?
现在却说什么 想跟我交往吗
You two really need some repairs.
你们两个真的欠修理耶
Please decide now
请你现在决定吧
Otherwise you will kill us to leave here
不然你就要杀了我们 才能离开这里
You are really heroic
你还真是壮烈呢
Don't you think I'm scary?
你不觉得我很可怕吗
It's scary but...
很可怕啊 但是…
you are beautiful
你很漂亮
Really
真是的
Don't laugh I'm risking my life now
不要笑 我现在可是赌上了性命耶
good
好
Brother, are you exaggerating?
哥 你会不会太夸张了
Will it?
会吗
What about you? What are you betting on?
你呢 你要赌上什么
Me?
我吗
Don't I dare to risk my life?
难道我不敢赌上我的性命吗
If you want me to risk my life, I won't hesitate
要我赌上性命 在所不辞
But if you don't date me
但你要是不跟我交往
I will still call your name
我还会喊着你的名字
Running around in the streets and alleys
在大街小巷跑来跑去
I haven’t put on my clothes yet… Okay…
还不把衣服穿起来… 好啦…
You two are really crazy.
你们两个真是神经病耶
This is the first time I meet someone He risked his life to date me
我还是第一次遇到有人 赌上性命说要跟我交往的
But if I have to choose between you
但如果要我在你们之中做选择
Who should I choose?
到底要选哪个人
What do you think?
你们说呢
Don't beat others
不要赢过人家
Never beat Tetsuo in any aspect
在任何方面 都不要赢过哲雄
What's the relationship between you two?
你们两个是什么关系
we are friends He is my brother
我们是朋友 他是我哥
what
什么
He is like my brother
他就像我的亲哥哥一样
We are one year apart
我们差一岁
The relationship between Brother Douxue’s family and our family unusual
斗学哥家跟我们家的关系 非比寻常
Brother Douxue’s family…
斗学哥他家…
Alas, it's probably because I ate too fast just now My stomach hurts a little
唉唷 大概是因为我刚刚吃太快 肚子有点痛呢
Tetsuo, I'm leaving first
哲雄 我先走了
Just keep talking.
你们就继续聊吧
sit down
坐下
But my stomach hurts
但我肚子痛
Don't go
不要走
sit down for me
给我坐下
sit down
坐下吧
Okay, it's not that difficult anyway.
好吧 反正这也不是什么难事
So are you willing to date us?
所以你愿意跟我们交往吗
OMG…
天啊…
I can meet you first
我可以先跟你们见面
Then who are you going to choose?
那你要选谁
Well, I need to think about this again.
这个嘛 我要再考虑看看
After all, you need to get along with each other a lot to understand each other.
毕竟要多多相处才能了解对方嘛
How long do you need to think about it?
那你需要多久的时间考虑
About...a year or so
大概…一年左右
Until then, we can just be friends, okay?
在那之前我们就当朋友 可以吧
Can't you decide faster?
你不能快一点决定吗
A year is a bit…
一年有点…
Brother, what do you think?
哥 你觉得呢
I think it doesn't matter if you go slower.
我觉得慢一点也无所谓啊
It's okay to go slower
再慢一点也行
Otherwise, you might as well never decide.
不然永远都不要决定也好
Do you want to wait until the day you wear your braids?
你想等到翘辫子那天喔
Okay, then just follow my advice.
好 那就照我的意见去做罗
You guys stand up
你们站起来
and you
还有你
Talk to me more easily from now on. Do you understand?
以后跟我说话轻松点 知道了没
Yes…
是的…
OK... OK
好…好喔
Okay friends, let's go then
好 朋友们 那我们走吧
Hey, let's go
喂 快走啦
"The years are gone forever"
"岁月一去不复返"
"I heard this sentence once when I was young and frivolous"
"年少轻狂时我曾听过这句话"
"My lover who left Wanshou Mountain"
"我那离开万寿山的爱人"
"Hope to see her again today"
"希望今天能再见到她一面"
"With my lips full of sorrow and joy"
"用我充满悲喜的双唇"
"Although I can speak freely, I just want to say"
"虽能够畅所欲言 但我只想说"
"I live so ignorantly"
"我活得是如此不懂事"
Come on, sergeants.
军士们 上啊
Come on
上啊
("College Troublemaker" "Chaos Diary") "I live so ignorantly"
("高校捣蛋鬼""乱中日记") "我活得是如此不懂事"
("0mother's apartment")
("0娘的公寓")
I just said that...
我就说是那样…
"Things said casually while turning around"
"转过身不经意说出的话"
"Do you understand what that means?"
"你明白那是什意思吗"
(I don’t know. It’s so difficult)
(不知道啦 好难)
"My love lit the fire of Mount Shakti"
"我的爱人 点燃了帝释山之火"
Come
来
"Burn all the weeds off the grave" I want to eat it, it’s so hot
"把坟墓的野草都烧尽" 我都要吃 好烫
Isn't it hot?
不烫吗
very hot
很烫
"My bittersweet mouth"
"我那甘苦参半的嘴"
Don't sit here. Come back to the team quickly.
别坐在这里 你快归队
"You can say anything"
"虽说可以说出任何话"
Hey your gun
喂 你的枪
(Nominations for the 10th National Assembly election are coming soon)
(第10届国会议员选举提名在即)
"I live so ignorantly"
"我活得是如此不懂事"
Lieutenant Colonel Huang
黄中校
If the sun shines brightly every day, the trees will die
若天天都是大太阳 树木会枯死
The trees must have experienced wind, rain and heavy snow
树木必须经历过风吹雨淋和大雪
to grow into a big tree
才能长成大树
Don't think you've been demoted
你别认为自己是被降职
Let's get along well
我们好好相处吧
thank you for your blessings
谢谢您的祝福
Please give me more advice in the future, Head of Teachers
以后请多多指教 师团长
Come
来
Use this money to boost morale
拿这些钱去提振一下士气
That's why I want to ask for your advice
我才要请你多多指教
thank you
谢谢
This guy treats me like a beggar
这家伙把我当乞丐啊
Team Leader Wu
吴组长
Let’s use the subsidy when making kimchi this year.
今年腌泡菜时拿去补贴吧
No need, Captain
不用了 队长
Take it
收下吧
You're the only one following me
只有你一个人跟着我来
thank you
谢谢您
what
什么
Trees go through wind, rain and heavy snow
树木要经历风吹雨淋和大雪
Am I a tree?
我是树吗
A guy who overestimates his abilities What does he think of our security headquarters?
不自量力的家伙 他把我们保安司令部当什么了
What era is it now?
都什么年代了
Team Leader Wu
吴组长
Go find out the details of that person
去查清那个人的底细
You can rest assured
您放心
I'll find out everything about him
我会把他的一切都查出来
And…
还有…
How are the opinions of the local gentry surveyed?
地方士绅的意见调查得怎么样
I'm doing it. I'm sorting it out by selection.
在做了 正在按照选区整理
This year’s parliamentary election Must win a big victory
今年的国会议员选举 一定要大获全胜
Only then can we go back
那样我们才回得去
yes
是的
(Bring your ID card to participate in the voting)
(携带身分证 全民参与投票)
The test results are out
考试成绩出来了
Are you all ready to hit the playground?
大家都准备好跑操场了吧
OK
好了
But this time there is a big change
不过这次有个重大的变化
Li Douxue Cui Zhexiong
李斗学 崔哲雄
Yes
是
Your ranking has changed
你们的排名换了
The first place in the school this time is Li Douxue
这次的全校第一名是李斗学
Full marks in every subject
各科都是满分
Come on, everyone applaud
来 大家鼓掌
Tetsuo
哲雄
congratulations
恭喜你
No more
没有啦
I guessed several questions. I was just lucky.
我猜了好几题 我只是运气好
You are taking this exam for Dingchen Did you study so hard?
这次考试你是为了定辰 才那么努力地念书吗
How could it be
怎么会
I'm just lucky
我只是运气好
Also
也是
It's a bit boring without any competition
没有竞争者 的确有点无聊
But I still feel bad
但心情还是不怎么样呢
Then let's go and relax
那我们去散散心吧
Dingchen should be waiting for us
定辰应该在等我们
I don't feel well today
我今天身体不太舒服
Go yourself
你自己去吧
Tetsuo… Douxue Tetsuo
哲雄… 斗学 哲雄
Why did you come here?
你怎么跑来这里
Hello
喂
Do you know how I did in this exam?
你们知道我这次考得怎么样吗
How is it
怎么样
My grades improved by eight places
我的成绩提升了八名
Great. So where did you get it?
好棒 所以你拿了第几名
Ranked 17th in the class and 190th in the school
全班第17名 全校第190名
I got into the top 200 for the first time
我第一次考进前200名
What are you doing?
干嘛
Do I also want to take the first and second place exams in the school?
我也要考全校第一第二吗
No
没有
you are great
你很棒
All of these...
这些都要…
Thank you Li Douxue
感谢你 李斗学
So
所以
You are going to a place with me today
你们今天要跟我一起去一个地方
Let's go
走吧
Why are you still standing there?
还站在那干嘛
Mom ordered a lot of food
妈叫了好多食物
Mom
妈
His name is Choi Cheol-woong
他叫崔哲雄
His name is Li Douxue
他叫李斗学
They compete for first and second place in the school all day long
他们一天到晚在争全校第一第二
This time Douxue won first place
这次斗学拿了第一名
Tetsuo took second place
哲雄拿了第二名
Really?
是吗
thank you
谢谢你们
I heard that you taught Dingchen how to read.
听说是你们教定辰念书的
No
没有
It's Dingchen who works very hard
是定辰自己很努力
That's right, I worked hard
没错 是我很努力
Will I not understand her?
我会不懂她吗
If it weren't for you
要不是你们
Even if the earth falls apart
就算天崩地裂
It's impossible for her to get into the top 200
她也不可能考进前200名
I could have passed without them
没有他们我也考得到
Your father is back from the hospital
你爸爸从医院回来啦
Long time no see Brother Zhongzhong
好久不见 忠诚哥
I was shocked when I received your call
接到你的电话 我吓了一跳
Although I also thought that one day
虽然我也想过总有一天
we will definitely meet again
我们一定会再见面
Me too. I heard about your coming to Lishui.
我也是 听说你来丽水的消息
shocked
吓了一跳
Take a seat
坐吧
You're still the same
你还是老样子呢
You haven't changed much
你也没什么变
do you have children
你有孩子了吗
i have a son
我有一个儿子
He should be in high school now
他应该上高中了吧
Yes
对
Fortunately you didn't marry me
幸好你没嫁给我
if you marry me
如果你嫁给我
You have to follow the army everywhere
就必须跟着军队到处跑
She has probably become a country aunt long ago
大概早就变成乡下的大婶了
sorry
对不起
If my father hadn't objected...
要不是我爸爸反对…
No, he was very prescient.
不 他很有先见之明
Is he in good health?
他身体还好吗
he passed away
他去世了
He died of a stroke due to losing the election.
他因为落选 脑中风过世的
So that's it
原来如此
sorry
对不起
It doesn't matter
没关系
but what happened
但是怎么了
Didn't you invite me here to have a normal conversation?
你不是约我来话家常的吧
Actually…
其实…
I have something to ask you
我有事想拜托你
Do you like to eat Chinese food?
你们爱吃中华料理啊
come to play occasionally
偶尔来玩
I'll treat you to food again
我再请你们吃
Okay, we will come often
好 我们会经常来的
Your father runs a lumber factory, right?
你爸爸是开木材厂的吧
Your family is very famous in Lishui
你们家在丽水很有名
Yes
对
Maybe because my grandfather participated in the independence movement
可能因为我爷爷参与过独立运动
I heard
我听说了
He is a very good person
他是个很优秀的人
what does your dad do
你爸爸是做什么的
Well...
这个嘛…
He is a farmer
他是种田的
It must be very hard
一定很辛苦吧
He has a son like you who is good at reading.
他有像你这么会念书的儿子
Must be very gratifying
一定很欣慰
Yes
是
Originally successful people were young We all live very hard.
本来成功的人小时候 都过得很刻苦嘛
Yes
是啊
Academic father
斗学的爸爸
He used to be a long-term worker in our family
本来在我们家当长工
My grandfather sent him to primary school
我爷爷送他去小学读书
Later, before he went to Manchuria to participate in the independence movement,
后来他要去满州参加独立运动前
And burned the slave contract with him
还烧了跟他的奴隶合约
Choi Cheol-woong, you are really...
崔哲雄 你真是…
No
不是
You are not a successful person I lived very hard when I was a child
你不是说成功的人 小时候都过得很刻苦
Douxue was born in a poor family
斗学出生在贫困的家庭
That's what I mean
我是这个意思
Successful people lived very hard when they were young I have never heard this sentence
成功的人小时候都过得很刻苦 这句话我没听过
But our family did suffer Grandpa Tetsuo takes great care of you
但我们家确实受到了 哲雄爷爷许多关照
me and my dad
我和我爸爸
I will never forget his great kindness in this life.
这辈子绝不会忘记他的大恩大德
Yes, you are so sensible
是啊 你真懂事
(Li Douxue)
(李斗学)
are you serious
你是认真的吗
I'm serious
对 我是认真的
His position is opposite to ours
他的立场和我们相反
So does his father
他父亲也是
That’s why the image of the South Korean Party will improve.
所以国韩党的形象才会变好啊
independence activist family
独立运动家家族
Opposition figures Also joined the Korean Party
反对派的在野人士 也加入了国韩党
In addition, it can also be cut off The financial resources of Hunan opposition members
除此之外还能切断 湖南在野党议员的财源
I'm just guessing
我只是随便猜猜
I'm so embarrassed when you put on such an expression
你摆出这种表情 我多尴尬
Please, Brother Zhongzhong
拜托你了 忠诚哥
Are we in this kind of relationship now?
我们现在变成这种关系了吗
But does your husband agree?
不过你丈夫同意了吗
Of course
当然
Help your husband
帮你老公
what can i get
我能得到什么
are you okay
你没事吧
Douxue
斗学
Wipe this for you
这给你擦
Let's go to the pharmacy
我们去药局吧
i'm fine
我很好
You go back
你回去吧
You are obviously not good
你明明不好
Go back quickly
你快回去
Brother
哥
I don't want to see you, go back quickly
我不想见到你 你快回去
Douxue
斗学
Really…
真的…
I'm sorry
很对不起
Do you call me friend like this?
你这样也叫朋友吗
Only you have self-respect
只有你有自尊心
Does Douxue have no self-esteem?
斗学没有自尊心吗
you are so despicable
你真卑鄙
This girl is really strong
这丫头 力气还真大
are you okay
你没事吧
I'm really sorry
真的很对不起
I really didn't mean that
我真的没有那个意思
Brother
哥
it's my fault
是我的错
Please forgive me once
你原谅我一次吧
Why don't I die?
我怎么不去死一死
I want to tear my mouth apart
我都想撕烂我的嘴了
Don't do this
你别这样
Just hit me until you are angry.
你打我吧 打到你气消为止
Tetsuo, you bad guy
哲雄 你这个坏蛋
Despicable person
卑鄙小人
Unloyal guy
不讲义气的家伙
A guy who is worse than a dog
连狗都不如的家伙
you hit me
你打我
A guy like me deserves to be beaten.
像我这种家伙被打也活该
Okay, it's okay
好了 没关系
It doesn't matter what
什么没关系
I want to be beaten by you
我想被你打
I understand your mood
我明白你的心情
Don't do this again
你别再这样了
Do you really understand how I feel?
你真的明白我的心情吗
Yes
对
Oops
哎呀
The water tastes so sweet
水喝起来真甜
Although you were born to me
虽然你是我生的
But looking at you really feels magical
但看着你真的觉得很神奇
why
为什么
Your father can only read a little bit
你爸爸就只会认一点字
I'm illiterate and can't understand anything.
我是文盲 什么也看不懂
How could I give birth to such an excellent child as you?
怎么会生出你这么优秀的孩子
And you come to help farm all day long
而且你一天到晚来帮忙种田
How come you still read so well?
怎么书还念得那么好
You reap what you sow. I have inherited it from you.
种豆得豆 我都是遗传你们的
If grandpa sends you to study
要是外公送你去念书
You can definitely become a judge or prosecutor
你一定能当上法官或检察官
right
对吧
If so
要是那样
I will definitely not be with your stupid person dad together
我一定不会和你那木讷的 爸爸在一起
I'll be with a handsome guy from Seoul
会跟首尔的帅哥在一起
right
对吧
Right
对啊
Dou Xue
斗学啊
Do you know when I am most relieved?
你知道我什么时候最欣慰吗
I woke up in the middle of the night
是半夜睡醒
I saw your back studying at the desk
看到你在书桌前念书的背影
I was most pleased then
那时我最欣慰
I feel like you will definitely become a big shot in the future
感觉你以后一定能成为大人物
You envy Tetsuo, right?
你很羡慕哲雄吧
No
没有
Don't worry, I'm already saving money for you
别担心 我已经在帮你存钱了
You can also live a good life in the future
你以后也能过上好日子
Why do you want to help me save money?
为什么要帮我存钱
I know my family has no money
我知道家里没钱
It’s not just money that can be saved
不是只有钱能存
Sometimes connections can be saved
有时候人脉也能存
what does that mean
那是什么意思
That's it anyway
总之就是这样
Go to the library quickly or go home and study
你快点去图书馆或回家念书吧
I'll do the rest
剩下的我来就好
i can help you
我可以帮你
You go back quickly, hurry up...
你快点回去吧 快点…
Come sit here and let's talk
你过来坐着 我们聊聊
Dad thinks
爸爸觉得
You have read enough books
你书已经念得够多了
Can you start going to the fields with daddy?
你能不能开始跟爸爸一起下田
what
什么
After Zhenyu gets married, she becomes someone else's family.
贞玉嫁人后就是别人家的人了
What to do with these fields?
这些田该怎么办
And just with these few acres of land
还有就凭这几亩田
I'm not sure I can send you to college
我没把握能送你去念大学
Dad, are you like this because of Tetsuo?
爸 你是因为哲雄才这样吗
Are you doing this because I beat Tetsuo in the exam?
你是因为我考赢哲雄才这样吗
What? Did Tetsuo cry again?
怎么 哲雄又哭了吗
Dad
爸
why can't i study
我为什么不能念书
Why can't I get first place in the exam?
我为什么不能考第一名
other parents
其他父母
I heard that my child came first in the exam It’s too late to praise
听到孩子考第一名 称赞都来不及了
Why don't you let me study
你为什么不让我念书
Don't let me take the first place in the exam
也不让我考第一名
Dad
爸
Although we received help from Grandpa Tetsuo
我们虽然受了哲雄爷爷的帮助
But I can repay them later
但可以之后再报答他们
This is not the feudal era
现在又不是封建时代
It’s not the Joseon era either
也不是朝鲜时代
Why do I have to live like a slave?
为什么我也要活得像个奴隶
you guy
你这家伙
How can you contradict dad?
怎么可以顶撞爸爸
Let you study more Are you going to climb on top of me?
再让你多念点书 你岂不是要爬到我头上了
That's why I don't let you study
所以我才不让你念书
Dad…
爸…
I won't talk back anymore
我不会再顶嘴了
I did that in a moment of madness
我是一时发疯才会那样
Dad
爸
I won't mess with Tetsuo and Tetsuo's family anymore.
我不会再招惹哲雄和哲雄家了
I swear it's true
我发誓 真的
Dad, I really want to study
爸 我真的很想念书
I can't hope to go to college
我不敢期望要上大学
But at least let me finish high school
但至少让我念完高中
From now on I will completely listen to dad
之后我就会完全听爸的
And I will never do Tetsuo again Sad thing
还有我绝对不会再做让哲雄 伤心的事了
Dad please
爸 求求你
please
求求你
Then…
那…
You transfer to another school
你转学吧
Why did you come here at this time?
你怎么会这个时候过来
Husband
老公
No problem anymore
没问题了
Finally got it done
终于搞定了
what does that mean
那是什么意思
You're going to be a member of Congress
你要当国会议员了
what
什么
You're about to be nominated
你要被提名了
Wife, come here
老婆 你过来一下
what on earth are you talking about
你到底在说什么
what was nominated
什么被提名
Have you ever met people from the Democratic Party?
难道你去见过民营党的人
You have to choose a side anyway.
反正都要选边站
Of course, you must choose the safest and most reliable backer.
当然要选最安全可靠的靠山
what
什么
You went to the South Korean Party
你去找了国韩党
are you crazy
你是不是疯啦
You're finally going to be nominated.
你终于要被提名了
Will soon become a member of Congress
很快就会成为国会议员
why are you so angry
你为什么要那么生气
You are really too much
你真是太过分了
Korea Party
国韩党
Do you want me to be an authoritarian dog?
你想让我当独裁主义的狗吗
Who told you to be a dog?
谁叫你当狗了
It’s not that you can’t catch tiger cubs if you don’t enter the tiger’s den.
不是说不入虎穴 焉得虎子
People from the opposition party go in and tell them the truth.
反对党的人进去和他们说真话
How good is this
这样多好
stand on the opposite side and oppose They won't listen at all
站在对立的立场反对 他们根本听不进去
Others have agreed to accept you
还有人家都同意接受你了
How can you say no?
你怎么能拒绝呢
It doesn't seem to make sense to you
看来跟你说不通
ok
好吧
That's fine. You can go by yourself.
那么好 你自己去吧
Husband
老公
I managed to help you negotiate it with great difficulty
我好不容易才帮你谈成
Our family can stand up again
我们家也能重新站起来
It’s your family that needs to stand up again
要重新站起来的是你家
My house has never fallen down
我家从来没倒下过
Husband
老公
We have lived together for more than 20 years Why don’t you understand me yet?
都一起生活20多年了 你怎么还不了解我
Yes
是啊
You donate all your hard earned money
你把辛苦赚来的钱都捐出去
Help others become members of Congress
帮助别人当上国会议员
Since you are so worried about the country and the people
既然那么忧国忧民
Can't you become a member of Congress yourself?
你不能自己去当国会议员吗
Don’t drink makgeolli with the farmers all day long
不要整天和种田的人喝马格利酒
I will stay in this small village my whole life.
一辈子就窝在这个小村子里
This small village is my hometown
这个小村子 是我的故乡
me as your wife
我作为你的妻子
I have been the daughter-in-law of this family for 20 years
作为这个家的媳妇过了20年
I never thought you were so stupid
我真没想到你这么傻
I run everywhere for you
我为了你到处奔波
So hard
那么辛苦
But you didn’t even say thank you
你却连句谢谢也没有
what
什么
Oops, such a thing can happen
哎呀 竟然有这种事
He won't eat even if the food is brought to him
食物端到他眼前他都不吃
I'm really angry
我真的好生气
So
所以啊
Uncle, he might listen to you.
叔叔 他可能会听你的话
what
什么
A rough guy like me
像我这种粗人
I only know things in the fields
只知道田里的事
Besides, the young master has a bad temper to begin with.
而且少爷本来就是牛脾气
Once you make up your mind, you rarely change your mind
下定决心的事很少再改变主意
lumber mill
木材厂
Just looks grand
只是看起来气派
Strictly speaking, those are bank assets.
严格说起来那是银行的资产
And…
而且…
Providing funds to opposition parties Looks like he's about to be discovered
向在野党提供资金的事 好像要被发现了
But his opponent said he would nominate him
但对手说要提名他
Refusal of nomination in this case
在这种情况下拒绝提名
They will definitely not let our family go
他们一定不会放过我们家
The bond between our families is so deep...
我们两家的缘分那么深…
Although starting in 1973
虽然从1973年开始
Unified rice cultivation
统一水稻栽培
Significantly increase domestic rice production
让国内的白米产量大幅提升
But the current level of self-sufficiency…
但目前自给自足的程度…
you guy
你这家伙
Hey brat
喂 臭小子
If you dare to mess with me, I will definitely kill you.
敢惹我 我一定杀了你
Brat
臭小子
Is that person named Li Douxue?
那个人叫李斗学吗
Without him, he is nothing.
没有他 他就什么都不是
2,500 won
2500韩元
That bastard
那个混蛋
welcome
欢迎
thank you
谢谢
Why hasn't the child's father come yet?
孩子的爸爸为什么还不来
He will be here soon
他马上就会来了
Has he really changed his mind?
他真的改变主意了吗
Say to the young master
对 少爷说
He will announce his candidacy today
他今天会公开参选消息
These are like-minded people
这些都是和他志同道合的人
We need people with electoral experience.
要用有选举经历的人才行
Doesn't he want to run as a member of the Democratic Party?
他不会是想以民营党身分参选吧
Candidates have been selected long ago
早就选好了候选人
Really?
是吗
President…
社长…
You are here...
你来啦…
I originally just wanted to live a low-key life
我本来只想低调地过日子
But this world won’t let me go
但这个世界不肯放过我
So this time
所以这次
I still have many shortcomings
还有诸多不足的我
Decided to participate in this election for members of Congress
决定参加这次国会议员的选举
Choi Young-sik…
崔英植…
thank you
谢谢
Everyone
各位
Drops of water can penetrate rocks
滴水也能滴穿岩石
Even a small force
既使是微小的力量
We must also work together
我们也要同心协力
Let’s defeat dictatorship together, everyone.
一起打倒独裁政治 各位
Choi Young-sik…
崔英植…
Captain, you guessed it right
队长 您猜对了
Fortunately he was not nominated in the first place
幸好一开始没提名他
I just said it
我就说了
He will never run as a member of the South Korean Party
他绝对不会以国韩党的身分参选
OK
好了
Start torturing him slowly
开始慢慢折磨他吧
Li Douxue
李斗学
Stop
你站住
why are you hiding from me
你为什么要躲我
I didn't hide from you
我没有躲你
You didn't even go to the library or contact me.
你都没去图书馆 也没联络我
I want to help with farm work
我要帮忙做农活
not like that
不是那样
You did it because your father worked as a long-term laborer You avoid me because you feel embarrassed
你是因为爸爸做过长工 觉得丢脸才躲我
You go back
你回去吧
Li Douxue, you are really too much.
李斗学 你真的好过分
What does it mean to be a long-term worker?
当过长工算什么
It’s not like being a traitor
又不是当卖国贼
What's there to be ashamed of?
有什么好丢脸的
The future is more important, right?
未来比较重要吧
You study as hard as you do now
你像现在这样努力念书
Who dares to look down on you when you get ahead in the future?
以后出人头地 谁敢瞧不起你
I transferred schools
我转学了
Went to Agricultural High School
去了农业高中
You have to study hard
你要认真念书
Take care of yourself
保重身体
Are you not going to see me anymore?
你以后都不打算见我了吗
Can't we be friends if we go to agricultural high school?
去读农业高中就不能当朋友吗
I've decided who to choose
我决定好要选谁了
why
为什么
why choose you
为什么选你
Why don't you choose Tetsuo?
不选哲雄吗
Don't ask stupid questions like this again
你以后别问这种傻问题
Just say you like me
说你喜欢我就好
Hello
喂
Are you a newcomer who just came here last week?
你是上礼拜才来的新人吧
As soon as they arrive, take the prisoners in Room 7 Beaten them all
一来就把7号房的囚犯 全打了一顿
The lunatic who was imprisoned in the punishment room Is that you?
那个被关进惩戒室的疯子 就是你吗
what crime have you committed
你犯了什么罪
Didn't answer
又不回答
kill
杀人
who did you kill
你杀了谁
Qi Yingzhuo, wake up
奇英卓 你醒醒
Qi Yingzhuo
奇英卓
Where did you throw the ball?
你球丢到哪里
Yingzhuo
英卓
The man you killed was named Qi Yingzhuo
你杀的那个人叫奇英卓
He is my only brother
他是我唯一的弟弟
The only one who comes to see me
唯一会来看我
Will give me money
会塞钱给我的
It's just him
就只有他而已
you know i'm here
你知道我在这里
How long have you been waiting for me, brat?
等你等了多久吗 臭小子
I didn't kill the person
人不是我杀的
Dare you say no?
还敢说不是
Li Douxue, you brat
李斗学你这臭小子
really not me
真的不是我
Tetsuo
哲雄
(Oasis Oasis)
(Oasis绿洲)
I'm dating you It’s not like I’m dating Tetsuo
我是跟你交往 又不是跟哲雄交往
Choi Cheol-woong, do you know him?
崔哲雄 你认识他吧
Yeah
嗯
Who hit you?
是谁动手打你的
Please go back
拜托你回去
Impolite girl
没礼貌的丫头
you bastard
你这混蛋
Ms. Jiang
姜女士
It’s hard to have such a noble and upright husband, right?
有这么高风亮节的丈夫很辛苦吧
Are you hiding something from me?
你是不是有事瞒着我
Brother, please save me
哥 拜托你救救我
why should i save you
我为什么要救你
Douxue, please say it’s not you
斗学 快说不是你
all because of you
全都是因为你
Never say you know me
绝对别说你认识我
Didn't you say you would be responsible for my life?
你不是说你会替我的人生负责
Didn't you say you would stand out? Then make it up to me, brat
你不是说你会出人头地 然后补偿我 臭小子